Setumadhava Giridhar Kathawate

206-739-4983 setugk8@gmail.com Seattle, WA <u>www.setumadhava.com</u>

About

Product designer having 3 years of experience in designing products for consumers and enterprise, seeking opportunities to solve complex user & business problems through elegant, research-informed product & experience designs. Other interests include Machine Learning & Behavioral Psychology.

Skills

Interaction Design, Prototyping, Axure, Framer, Invision, Interface & Visual design, Foundations of Machine Learning, Internal Tool Design, Enterprise Software Design, Wireframes, Sketch, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, <u>UserTesting.com</u>, Using User Research methodologies to analyze & measure user behavior, Contextual Inquiry, User Interviews, Personas, Designing usable & accessible patterns & products, HTML/CSS/SASS, Python, Arduino, Cross Functional Collaboration skills, Design strategy, Agile methodologies, Machine Learning basics, Android (Material) & iOS design languages.

Relevant Courses

User-Centered Design, Usability Studies, Data Science for UX Researchers, Visual Communication, Interaction Design & Prototyping, Machine Learning (Coursera).

Experience

UW MEDICINE, UX DESIGNER

DEC 2017 - PRESENT

Designed web & mobile experiences for UW Medicine's website collaborating with Developers,
Content & SEO strategists. Responsibilities included creating wireframes, prototypes, running
remote usability studies, visual design and creating high-fidelity mockups.

EVENTOSAUR, CO-FOUNDER & PRODUCT DESIGNER

MAR 2015 - PRESENT

 Leading the design & research efforts to design a Sass tool (mobile web app) to help event vendors manage their orders, inventory and team engagements. Process includes sketching, creating wireframes, running usability studies, building a design system & visual design.

PREMERA BLUE CROSS, UX DESIGNER

MAY 2017 - DEC 2017

- Led the UX efforts to design a Provider Search tool to help Premera's customers confidently find the providers or facilities covered by their insurance plan.
- Average customer satisfaction score went up from 2.8 to 4.1 (on a scale of 1-5) after shipping the new search experience.

EXPEDIA INC, INTERACTION DESIGN INTERN

JUN 2016 - SEP 2016

- Conceptualized & designed a mobile web interface to explore alternative hotel shopping experience for Expedia's customers by simplifying the beds & occupancy preferences, room browsing & checkout process.

Education

MASTER'S IN HUMAN CENTERED DESIGN & ENGINEERING

SEP 2015 - MAR 2017

The University of Washington, Seattle; GPA 3.92/4.0

BACHELOR'S IN ELECTRONICS & COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING

AUG 2006 - JUN 2010

Visvesvaraya Technological University, Bangalore, India; GPA 6.9/10.0

Awards

BEST GRADUATE CAPSTONE PROJECT - PUMP IT UP

JUN 2017

University of Washington, Seattle

Designed an Android app and an IOT system prototypes that provide residents contextual information & better control over existing water systems to reduce water waste in India.